RAHMI ALKAN

Email: rahmialkan112@gmail.com | Mobile: +447360721848 | Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/rahmi-alkan | Address: Belfast, UK

SUMMARY

A Biomedical Engineer with **1+ year** hands on experience in clinical device training, technical support, regulatory standards, and assisted medical professionals navigate the complexities of modern medical equipment. Passonate to develop and contribute in **QMS** and **regulatory complaince** of medical devices.

EDUCATION

MSc in Msc Biomedical Engineering Science | Ulster University, Belfast | 2022 - 2023

- Modules: Medical Device Design, Bioinstrumentation, Quality Improvement
- **Publication:** Computational Evaluation of IABP, Impella 2.5, TandemHeart and Combined IABP and Impella 2.5 Support in Cardiogenic Shock

BSc Biomedical Engineering, Grade: 1st Class: 73.75% | Karabuk University, Turkey | 2014 - 2018

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ecommerce Trader | eBAY Self Business Account | November 2022 - Present | Remote, UK

- Conducted market research in Zik Analytics and negotiated prices, increasing sales by 15% in 3 months.
- Improved product photos and listing templates on **canva**, achieving a ~20% increase in viewing rates.
- Conducted product analysis to ensure compliance with eBay standards prior to listing.

Biomedical Engineer | Dunya Hospital | Nov 2020 - Sep 2021 | Batman, Turkey

- Provided on-site consulting and technical guidance to medical personnel, ensuring optimal performance
- Delivered **technical support** and improved performance of medical equipment in a high-volume hospital with a patient-to-staff ratio of **10:1**, covering ECGs, Anesthesia, Ventilator, and patient monitor.
- Streamlined medical equipment calibration procedures, enhancing operational efficiency by 15%.

Inspector(Work and Travel Programme) | Vail Resort | Jun 2018 - Oct 2018 | Crested Butte, Colorado, US

- Inspected 30+ hotel rooms daily, following the hotel standards strictly, reducing maintenance issues, and increasing guest satisfaction by **10%**, reflected in housekeepers' tips.
- Repaired issues with electronic hotel room appliances, such as damaged circuits, faulty wiring and broken cords.

Intern Biomedical Engineer | Dunya Hospital | Jun 2017 - Aug 2017 | Batman, Turkey

- Performed detailed quality control checks and regulatory inspections on various medical equipment like x-ray machines, autoclaves and ECG machines to ensure they met industry standards, improving patient safety.
- Wrote daily reports on repairs and technical papers to share knowledge and improve hospital processes.

Intern Biomedical Engineer | Atatürk Eğitim ve Araştırma Hospital | Jul 2016 - Sep 2016 | Izmir, Turkey

- Trained in analyzing and repairing various medical electronic equipment, ranging from patient monitor to x-ray engine, resulting in a ~10% reduction in equipment failures.
- Utilized soldering techniques to repair electrical wires and components, ensuring safe and reliable operation of equipment across the hospital.

LANGUAGES, SKILLS AND CERTIFICATES

- Languages: English (advanced proficiency), Turkish (native), Kurdish(native)
- **Skills:** MS Office Suite, Regulatory complaince, Technical Documentation, Interpersonal Relationships, Troubleshooting, Academic Research, Validation IQ OQ PQ
- Certifications: ISO 13485, ISO 9001, ISO 9000, COSSH, Health and Safety, Quality Assurance Manager Training